Abdullah Choudhry

Winona, MN 55987 | (507)-990-6004 | abdullah_m_c@hotmail.com

OBJECTIVE

Current student at Winona State University as a Computer Science major with a Data Science minor. Strong teamwork and interpersonal skills through years of retail experience. Motivated to utilize my relevant experience, expertise and problem-solving skills in a professional setting.

EDUCATION

Winona State University - Winona, MN

Aug 2017 – Present

- Bachelor's in Computer Science: (Expected May 2021)
- Minor in Data Science GPA: 3.70 Honors: Dean's List

Relevant Coursework:

• Computer Systems, Applied Database Management, Human-Computer Interaction, Artificial Intelligence, Software Engineering, Principles of Programming Languages, Web Programming, Operating Systems, Computation Theory

SKILLS / STRENGTHS

- Programming Languages: Java, C#, SQL, HTML w/ Bootstrap, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, R, Python
- **Tools:** Visual Studios (2017, 2019), Eclipse, MySQL Workbench, GitHub, TFS, Remote Desktop, R Studio, Open refine
- Hardware: Desktop building/repair,
- Additional Experience: Testing, Automated Testing, SCRUM, Team Programming, Customer Service, Time Management, Critical Thinking

WORK EXPERIENCE

Winona State University - Winona, MN

Software Testing and Development Lab – Watlow

Feb 2020 – Present

- Working with proprietary software, providing testing and other technical services to Watlow with a team of fellow students.
- Learning technical skills in a real business environment.

Sept 2019 – Jan 2020

Teaching Assistant

- Creating opportunities for students in introductory computer science courses to further understand coursework by explaining complex concepts; assisting with in-class labs
- Grading assignments and exams
- Holding office hours for individual discussions with students

Hy-Vee - Rochester, MN & Winona, MN

Oct 2015 - Feb 2010

Frozen Clerk

- Provided a greater customer experience by working registers and escorting customers to products.
- Increased department productivity and sales through unloading trucks, stocking products, organizing/facing shelves, assisting in inventory and replenishments

PROJECTS

• Created an application that attempts to find statistical dependencies in given datasets and model them with Bayesian networks for causal analysis and prediction

EXTRACURRICULAR EXPERIENCE

Student Council, Rochester Century High School

Sept 2014 – June 2017

Improved school experience through sharing the student body's ideas/concerns, organizing charity fundraisers, and school-wide activities in collaboration with school administration
Computer Science Club, WSU
Spring 2017 – Present

• Expanding knowledge of technology through fun and engaging activities